<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Paolo Usero</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/"/>
 <updated>2014-07-18T16:15:22-04:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Paolo Usero</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>kinks in productivity</title>
   <link href="/2014/07/18/Productivity-Kinks/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/07/18/Productivity-Kinks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been rather unproductive these past few months, and I think I know
 the reason why, I&amp;#39;m just not sure how to go about solving it. It&amp;#39;s
 procrastination, the eternal foe again, and this time it&amp;#39;s because of a
 fear of decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that fear is a mix of different things; it could be self-doubt
 about if I&amp;#39;m making the right decisions for myself, fear of looking stupid 
or saying the wrong thing, and fear of change.
  So stemming from those fears, I downloaded a bunch of games and played
 them all till the wee hours of the night.  Not quite the ultra productive
 summer I envisioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst all this, I did actually help out with the house a bit by cleaning up my little corner upstairs, clearing out a bunch of clothes to go to goodwill (the clothes aren&amp;#39;t in the room anymore, but they&amp;#39;re not at goodwill yet, so they&amp;#39;re in car purgatory at the moment), the website&amp;#39;s blogging stuff is up and running, and I&amp;#39;m chugging along with the Brother&amp;#39;s Karamazov, so not everything is in vain. Still, there was a lot I wanted to accomplish to get to a point where I would&amp;#39;ve been satisfied with myself, and really, there is still a chance that the proverbial ship can change direction and steer back into the right track, but I&amp;#39;m finding myself in very familiar territory and feeling procrastination-deadline-y again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;ALREADY FRIDAY&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, even in just writing this post, I got tired at 2 am and went to sleep, so it&amp;#39;s friday. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;GOAT ME&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/2b0yf8/good_students_how_do_you_go_about_getting_good/cj0qre2&quot;&gt;I found this reddit post&lt;/a&gt; about how to make learning stick - with the amusing acronym of GOAT ME. I&amp;#39;ll leave you to read the post, but the reason it struck me is that it seemed to draw the same conclusions as other ideas I&amp;#39;ve found online - Tim Ferris, Cal Newport, and Scott H Young all seem to say very similar things with regard to learning. I should really apply that to my habit/productivity/process learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;NO TIME LEFT vs ALL THE TIME IN THE WORLD&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another sentiment in that thread (and in another post I was reading about procrastination) about how the perception of how much time you have affects the amount of stuff you get done. If you perceive that you have all the time in the world, then of course you&amp;#39;re gonna act like that - you&amp;#39;ll never get to the important stuff because there&amp;#39;ll always be an extra minute or hour somewhere where you can do that project or whatever. If you always operate under the idea of time scarcity, or just think that you will never have time again to do the important, will you do it? Again, I&amp;#39;ve encountered this idea in a thousand different ways, but it never stuck for some reason. In the few hours I&amp;#39;ve thought about it though, it seems I&amp;#39;m a lot more motivated to do things when I think to myself that &amp;quot;I will never have this time again&amp;quot;. Maybe this time it&amp;#39;ll work? We&amp;#39;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Personal Process</title>
   <link href="/2014/07/09/Personal-Process/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/07/09/Personal-Process</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick test to find out if the personal tags works as it should.
 If you find this page, it&amp;#39;s okay, it&amp;#39;s not entirely private, but I&amp;#39;d rather not have this stuff clutter up the front page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; It&amp;#39;ll probably mostly just introspectives on my current projects and will be more diary/journal like, in contrast to the front page which I want to be more explanatory and structured.&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Microeconomics Self-Study Process</title>
   <link href="/2014/06/27/Microeconomics-Self-Study-Process/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/06/27/Microeconomics-Self-Study-Process</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I just finished up a Micro-economics test, and I&amp;#39;m glad that&amp;#39;s over. Don&amp;#39;t follow what I did:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallow in discomfort for a month or two.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passively watch powerpoints, while thinking I&amp;#39;m being productive at &lt;em&gt;le Starbucks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procrastinate effervescently&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did work however, toward the end of the studying stint, was taking the tests and seeing feedback either immediately 
or right after taking the test: I got to hone in ambgiguity much quicker, and things started clicking much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All along this process, I was trying to implement what the internet has collectively taught me on how to study, and I could hardly
figure out what was wrong until I noticed something: There were a lot of &amp;#39;entry&amp;#39; points to the subject matter, but from
those entry points I couldn&amp;#39;t really get my head into the right thought process. If worded or presented differently I would
get it, but not from random jumping points. This may or may not prove to be important in the future, but we&amp;#39;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it&amp;#39;s time to focus on the next set of challenges. I&amp;#39;m slowly getting to a good operational point, where new things that come up can be easily handled and
I can maintain good progress in existing projects. This site, Trello, Syncing Email and Windows, github, bitbucket all funnel into this &amp;#39;goal&amp;#39;, and I hope that
I can get to that elusive &amp;#39;goal&amp;#39; sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Testing Screen Capture on Windows 8.1</title>
   <link href="/2014/06/12/Testing-ScreenCap/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/06/12/Testing-ScreenCap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So apparently Windows 8/8.1 borked a lot of the simpler screen recording programs, so it took me a bit before I settled on Camtasia. Compared to the simpler screencap programs, the process of screen recording and uploading everything is two or three more steps longer, but being able to record everything including metro apps is great. Hopefully I can streamline this process way down so that things I&amp;#39;m working on can be uploaded quickly and make this a fun place. I&amp;#39;m using http://gfycat.com to host the screen recordings, because HTML5 videos are faster than gifs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen Capture process:&lt;br&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camtasia recorder - record screen&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camtasia studio - convert .camrec to .gif&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gfycat - upload .gif to Gfycat (results in hosted .gif and html5 vid)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;github - post new .md file for blog and embed gfycat link.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual screen cap is kind of useless, but it illustrates  the fact that I can actually screen cap between both desktop and metro apps seamlessly.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://test.gfycat.com/gfycat_test_may18.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gfyitem&quot; data-title=false data-autoplay=true data-controls=true data-expand=true data-id=&quot;UnawareMinorDarklingbeetle&quot; &gt;&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Godzilla at the Beach (First Post!)</title>
   <link href="/2014/05/26/Godzilla-Beach/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/2014/05/26/Godzilla-Beach</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Godzilla at the Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this is my first real post on this site. Whatever I&amp;#39;m making that&amp;#39;s presentable, may end up here in the future. We&amp;#39;ll see what happens! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../public/images/Godzilla_Beach.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
